anchor.fm 2016-11-13

# Anchor - Radio by the people - Terms of Service

## Anchor FM Inc. Privacy Policy

Date of Last Revision: February 7, 2016 

### Our Policy

Welcome to the Anchor FM Inc. (“Anchor”, “we”, “us” and/or “our”) service, including our websites, SMS, APIs, email notifications, applications, buttons, widgets, ads and other services (collectively, the “Anchor Services”). The Anchor Services are designed to offer users of the Anchor Services (collectively, “Users,” “you,” or “your”) the opportunity to easily create and share audio recordings with other Users. This Privacy Policy describes how Anchor collects, uses and discloses information, including Personal Information. 

“Personal Information” means information that alone or when in combination with other information may be used to readily identify, contact, or locate you, such as: name, address, email address, phone number, photograph or voice recording. 

### Information We Collect and Use

When you interact with us through the Anchor Services, we may collect information, including Personal Information , as described below: 

#### Information Personal Information That You Provide Through the Anchor Services:

We collect Personal Information from you when you voluntarily provide such information, such as when you contact us with inquiries, respond to one of our surveys, register for access to the Anchor Services or use certain Anchor Services, including when done so through their integration into social media services, such as Facebook or Twitter (“Social Media Services”). By providing us with Personal Information, you are consenting to our use of it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you provide Personal Information through the Anchor Services, you acknowledge and agree that such Personal Information may be transferred from your current location to the offices and servers of Anchor and the authorized third parties referred to herein. 

#### Cookies, Automatic Data Collection, and Related Technologies:

When you visit the Anchor Services, we and third parties that provide functionality on the Anchor Services may engage, receive and record information from your use of the Anchor Services and server logs from your browser, including your IP address, and from cookies and similar technology. This information is used to track the total number of Users, the number of visitors of each page to our websites, and the domain names of our Users’ Internet service providers. Most browsers allow you to block and delete cookies. However, if you do that, the Anchor Services may not work properly. 

#### Aggregated Data:

We may anonymize and aggregate data collected through the Anchor Services and use it for any purpose. Such information does not identify you individually. 

#### Social Media:

Through the Anchor Services, you may choose to access certain Social Media Services. When you elect to access and use the Social Media Services, you will be sharing your information (which will include personal information if you elect to share such information) with those Social Media Services. As with other Third Party Sites, the information that you share with the Social Media Services will be governed by the privacy policies and terms of service of the providers of such Social Media Services and not by the Anchor’s policies and procedures. You may also be able to modify your privacy settings with these Social Media Services to, for example, control what information the Social Media Services disclose to other entities, including Anchor. When you provide Anchor access to your Social Media Services account, we will collect relevant information necessary to enable the Anchor Services to access that Social Media Service, however you will provide your login information, like your password, directly to such Social Media Service (and not to Anchor). 

As part of the integration of the Anchor Services with your Social Media Services account, the Social Media Service will provide Anchor with access to certain information that you have provided to such Social Media Service, including but not limited to post-related meta data from your Twitter feed or Facebook wall (e.g., post type, date of creation, date of update, post creator, permanent link, and the number of “Likes” and “Comments”), and “friends” or users you are “following”. Anchor does not download, save, or store your photos, videos, or status messages posted on your Social Media Services accounts unless you grant it permission to do so. To access your Social Media Services account, we provide a link that directs you to a Social Media Service, like Twitter and Facebook, where you may access the Anchor Services directly. We will use, store and disclose such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and, if and to the extent applicable, the policies of such Social Media Services. However, please remember that the manner in which Social Media Services use, store and disclose your information is governed by the policies of the applicable Social Media Services provider, and, as a result, Anchor shall not have any liability or responsibility for the privacy practices or other actions of Social Media Services that may be enabled within and/or otherwise accessible through the Anchor Services. 

#### Posts, Following, Lists and other Public Information:

The Anchor Services are primarily designed to help you share information with the world. Most of the information you provide us through the Anchor Services is information you are asking us to make public. Your public information includes the messages you post; the metadata provided with such posts, such as when you posted and the client application you used to post; the language, country, and time zone associated with your account; and the lists you create, people you follow, posts you mark as likes, and many other bits of information that result from your use of the Anchor Services. We may use this information to make inferences, like what topics you may be interested in, and to customize the content we show you, including ads. Our default is almost always to make the information you provide through the Anchor Services public for as long as you do not delete it. The Anchor Services broadly and instantly disseminate your public information to a wide range of users, customers, and services. For instance, your public user profile information and public posts are immediately delivered via SMS and our APIs to our partners and other third parties, including search engines, developers, and publishers that integrate Anchor Services content into their services, and institutions such as universities and public health agencies that analyze the information for trends and insights. When you share information or content via the Anchor Services, you should think carefully about what you are making public. 

#### Location Information:

Anchor may receive information about your location. For example, you may choose to publish your location in your posts and in your Anchor profile. You may also tell us your location when you set your trend location on the Anchor Services. We may also determine location by using other data from your device, such as precise location information from GPS, information about wireless networks or cell towers near your mobile device, or your IP address. We may use and store information about your location to provide features of our Anchor Services, such as to improve and customize the Anchor Services, for example, with more relevant content like local trends, stories, ads, and suggestions for people to follow. Additional Information: You may provide us with profile information to make public on the Anchor Services, such as a short biography, your location, your website, or a picture. You may choose to upload your address book so that we can help you find users you know or help other users find you. We may later make suggestions to you and other users based on imported address book contacts. You can delete your imported address book contacts at any time.  If you email us, we may keep your message, email address and contact information to respond to your request. If you connect your account on our Anchor Services to your account on another service in order to cross-post between our Anchor Services and that service, the other service may send us your registration or profile information on that service and other information that you authorize. This information enables cross-posting, helps us improve the Anchor Services, and is deleted from our Anchor Services within a few weeks of your disconnecting from our Anchor Services your account on the other service. 

Anchor uses the Personal Information you provide in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. In general, Anchor uses information for the following purposes: 

* to customize the advertising and content you see,
* to fulfill your requests for products and services, 
* to improve the Anchor Services, contact you, conduct research, and provide reporting to third parties

If you provide Personal Information for a certain reason, we may use the Personal Information in connection with the reason for which it was provided. For instance, if you contact us by e-mail, we will use the Personal Information you provide to answer your question or resolve your problem. Also, if you provide Personal Information in order to obtain access to the Anchor Services, we will use your Personal Information to provide you with access to such services and to monitor your use of such services. Anchor and its subsidiaries, affiliates and service providers may also use your Personal Information and other personally non-identifiable information collected through the Anchor Services to help us improve the content and functionality of the Anchor Services, to better understand our users and to improve the Anchor Services. Anchor and its affiliates may use this information to contact you in the future to tell you about services or products we believe will be of interest to you or other Anchor Services-related announcements. If we do so, each communication we send you will contain instructions permitting you to "opt-out" of receiving future communications. In addition, if at any time you wish not to receive any future communications or you wish to have your name deleted from our mailing lists, please contact us as indicated below. Anchor reserves the right to send you notifications regarding your account even if you opt-out of all voluntary email notifications. 

#### Targeted Advertisement:

Anchor may display targeted advertisements based on Personal Information. Third parties (including ad serving companies) may assume that Users who interact with, view, or click targeted advertisements meet the targeting criteria (e.g., women ages 18–24 from a particular geographic area). Anchor does not provide any Personal Information to the advertiser when a User interacts with or views a targeted advertisement. However, by interacting with or viewing an advertisement you are consenting to the possibility that the third party will make the assumption that you meet the targeting criteria used to display the advertisement. 

#### Managing Cookies and Do Not Track:

Our Services currently do not respond to “Do Not Track” (DNT) signals and operate as described in this Privacy Policy whether or not a DNT signal is received. If Anchor intends on using any Personal Information in any manner that is not consistent with this Privacy Policy, you will be informed of such anticipated use prior to or at the time at which the Personal Information is collected. 

### Our Disclosure of Your Personal Information and Other Information:

Anchor is not in the business of selling your information. We consider this information to be a vital part of our relationship with you. There are, however, certain circumstances in which we may share your Personal Information with certain third parties without further notice to you, as set forth below: 

#### User Consent or Direction:

We may share or disclose your information at your direction, such as when you authorize a third-party web client or application to access your account. Other users may share or disclose information about you, such as when they mention you. 

#### Non-Private or Non-Personal Information:

We may share or disclose your non-private, aggregated or otherwise non-personal information, such as your public user profile information, public posts, the people you follow or that follow you, or the number of users who clicked on a particular link (even if only one did), or reports to advertisers about unique users who saw or clicked on their ads after we have removed any private personal information (such as your name or contact information). 

#### Vendors and Service Providers:

We may share any information, including Personal Information, that we receive with vendors and service providers and use it for any purpose. 

#### Business Transfers:

As we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event of a merger, acquisition, financing due diligence, reorganization, bankruptcy, receivership, sale of company assets or transition of service to another provider, Personal Information may be part of the transferred or sold business or assets. 

#### Related Companies:

We may also share your Personal Information with our Related Companies for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy. 

#### Agents, Consultants and Related Third Parties:

Anchor, like many businesses, sometimes hires other companies to perform certain business-related functions. Examples of such functions include mailing information, maintaining databases, processing payments, and providing analysis relating to User experience and behavior when using the Anchor Services. When we employ another company to perform a function of this nature, we only provide them with the information that they need to perform their specific function. 

#### Legal Requirements:

Anchor may disclose your Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (i) comply with a legal obligation, (ii) protect and defend the rights or property of Anchor, (iii) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of the Anchor Services or the public, (iv) protect against legal liability or suspected fraud, or (v) investigate, prevent, or take action regarding violations of Anchor’s Terms of Use. 

### Third Party Websites and Applications:

This Privacy Policy only applies to the Anchor Services. The Services may contain links to other websites not operated or controlled by Anchor (the “Third Party Sites”). We do not own, control or operate such linked sites, and we are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of such linked sites. Privacy policies and practices for such linked sites may differ from this Privacy Policy and our practices. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of such linked sites before disclosing personal information on Third Party Sites. 

### Children:

Anchor does not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any Personal Information through the Anchor Services. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s Internet usage and to help enforce our Privacy Policy by instructing their children never to provide Personal Information through the Anchor Services without their permission. If you have reason to believe that a child under the age of 13 has provided Personal Information to Anchor through the Anchor Services, please contact us, and we will endeavor to delete that information from our databases. 

### Links to Other Web Sites:

This Privacy Policy applies only to the Anchor Services. The Anchor Services may contain links to other web sites not operated or controlled by Anchor (the “Third Party Sites”). The policies and procedures we described here do not apply to the Third Party Sites. The links from the Anchor Services do not imply that Anchor endorses or has reviewed the Third Party Sites. We suggest contacting those sites directly for information on their privacy policies. 

### Security:

You use Anchor Services at your own risk. Anchor takes steps to protect the Personal Information provided via the Anchor Services from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. However, no Internet or e-mail transmission is ever fully secure or error free. In particular, e-mail sent to or from the Anchor Services may not be secure. Therefore, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us via e-mail. Please keep this in mind when disclosing any Personal Information to Anchor via the internet. We cannot control the actions of other Users with whom you may choose to share information. Therefore, we cannot, and do not, guarantee that information or content posted by a User on or through the Anchor Services will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Anchor Services or Social Media Services. 

### Other Terms and Conditions:

Your access to and use of the Anchor Services is subject to any additional terms applicable to such Anchor Services that may be posted on the Anchor Services from time to time, including without limitation, Anchor’s Terms of Use available at https://anchor.fm/tos. 

### Changes to Anchor’s Privacy Policy:

The Anchor Services and our business may change from time to time. As a result, at times it may be necessary for Anchor to make changes to this Privacy Policy. Anchor reserves the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time without prior notice. Anchor strives to provide notifications to Users in a timely manner, but is not responsible for lost or late notifications. Please review this policy periodically, and especially before you provide any Personal Information. This Privacy Policy was last updated on the date indicated above. Your continued use of the Anchor Services after any changes or revisions to this Privacy Policy shall indicate your agreement with the terms of such revised Privacy Policy. 

### International Users:

If you are visiting from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use, please note that by providing your information to the Anchor Services you are agreeing to the transfer of your information to the United States and processing globally. By providing your information you consent to any transfer and processing in accordance with this Policy. 

### Access to Information; Contacting Anchor:

To keep your Personal Information accurate, current, and complete, please contact us as specified below. We will take reasonable steps to update or correct Personal Information in our possession that you have previously submitted via the Anchor Services. Please also feel free to contact us if you have any questions about Anchor’s Privacy Policy or the information practices of the Anchor Services. 

You may contact us as follows:  
Anchor FM Inc.  
c/o Privacy Dept.  
79 Madison Ave.  
New York, NY 10016
